Finding aid to the Jennette Perry Lee Papers CA.MS.00033
Smith College Archives
Jennette Perry Lee Papers
1875-1946
Smith College Archives
Lee, Jennette Barbour Perry, 1860-1951.
CA.MS.00033
5.0 linear feet (12 containers)
Biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, writings, etc., of Jennette Barbour Perry Lee, professor of English at Smith College and author.
Biographical / Historical
Jennette Barbour Perry Lee was born on November 10, 1861, in New England, where she would spend many years of her life. She was admitted to Smith College in April of 1883, and after graduation in 1886 worked as an instructor at the Grant Collegiate Institute in Chicago, where she taught Philosophy, Rhetoric and Composition. Later, she taught at the Wheaton Academy, Vassar, and Western Reserve. In 1886, she married Gerald Stanley Lee, a pastor, author, editor and lecturer. In 1901, she returned to Smith as an instructor, and in 1904 was officially appointed as an Associate Professor in English. She was a member of the faculty until 1913, teaching popular courses in Appreciation and Criticism. She was a member of the Hosts of Philistia, also known as the American Academy of Immortals. In her later years, she gave up her academic career for a very successful writing career. She died on October 16, 1951.
Scope and Contents
The Jennette Perry Lee papers contain biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, writings and newspaper clippings covering Lee's career as a faculty member and Smith College and other aspects of her personal life.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Jennette Perry Lee papers came to the College Archives from a number of sources.
Lee, Jennette Barbour Perry, 1860-1951.
- Biography and Genealogy, 1883-1935 (Box 896, Folder 1)
- Bibliographies, undated (Box 896, Folder 2)
- Finances, undated (Box 896, Folder 3)
- Lecture Notes, undated (Box 896, Folder 4)
- Rest Research Center, undated (Box 896, Folder 5)
- Student Papers, undated (Box 896, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1886 (Box 896, Folder 7)
- Correspondence- Atlantic Monthly, 1897-1901 (Box 897, Folder 1)
- Correspondence- Branch, Anna Hempstead, 1906-1915 (Box 897, Folder 2)
- Correspondence- Burton, Richard, undated (Box 897, Folder 3)
- Correspondence- Casamajor, Dr. Louis, 1934-1936 (Box 897, Folder 4)
- Correspondence- The Century Co., 1906-1929 (Box 897, Folder 5)
- Correspondence- The Criterion, 1900 (Box 897, Folder 6)
- Correspondence- Curtis Brown Ltd., 1918-1925 (Box 897, Folder 7)
- Correspondence- Dodd, Mead And Company, 1913 (Box 897, Folder 8)
- Correspondence- Edison, Mrs. Thomas Alva, undated (Box 897, Folder 9)
- Correspondence- Ginn and Company Publishers, 1924-1929 (Box 897, Folder 10)
- Correspondence- Harper and Brothers, 1911 (Box 897, Folder 11)
- Correspondence- Hurst and Blackett Limited, 1922-1925 (Box 897, Folder 12)
- Correspondence- International Magazine Company, Inc., 1927 (Box 897, Folder 13)
- Correspondence- Ladies Home Journal, 1913-1922 (Box 897, Folder 14)
- Correspondence- Lee, Gerald Stanley, 1912-1921 (Box 897, Folder 15)
- Correspondence- Lee, Gerald Stanley, 1922 (Box 897, Folder 16)
- Correspondence- Lee, Gerald Stanley, 1924 (Box 897, Folder 17)
- Correspondence- Lee, Gerald Stanley, 1925-1931; undated (Box 897, Folder 18)
- Correspondence- Lee, Geraldine, 1911-1921 (Box 897, Folder 19)
- Correspondence- Lee, Geraldine, 1922-1924; undated (Box 897, Folder 20)
- Correspondence- Miscellaneous, 1910-1945 (Box 897, Folder 21)
- Correspondence- Morss, Mr., undated (Box 897, Folder 22)
- Correspondence- Munsey, Frank A., 1900 (Box 897, Folder 23)
- Correspondence- N.Y. League of American Pen Women, 1922-1923 (Box 897, Folder 24)
- Correspondence- Perry, Mr., 1903-1905 (Box 897, Folder 25)
- Correspondence- Pictorial Review, 1922-1927 (Box 897, Folder 26)
- Correspondence- Reynolds, Paul R., 1912-1920 (Box 897, Folder 27)
- Correspondence- regarding death of Geraldine in 1931, 1931-1936 (Box 897, Folder 28)
- Correspondence- Charles Scribner's Sons, 1921 (Box 897, Folder 29)
- Correspondence- Stanley House, 1906 (Box 897, Folder 30)
- Correspondence- Thwing, Charles Franklin, undated (Box 897, Folder 31)
- Correspondence- Whitford House, 1930 (Box 897, Folder 32)
- Journals- Jan-Mar, 1879 (Box 898, Folder 1)
- Journals- Mar-May, 1879 (Box 898, Folder 2)
- Journals- May-Aug, 1879 (Box 898, Folder 3)
- Journals- Sept-?, 1888 (Box 898, Folder 4)
- Journals, Jul 1913-Apr 1914 (Box 898, Folder 5)
- Journals, May 1914-Dec 1915 (Box 898, Folder 6)
- Journals, Jan 1916-Jul 1917 (Box 898, Folder 7)
- Journals, Sept 1917-Mar 1919 (Box 898, Folder 8)
- Journals, Mar 1919-Dec 1920 (Box 899, Folder 1)
- Journals, Dec 1920-May 1921 (Box 899, Folder 2)
- Journals, Feb-Jun. 1922 (Box 899, Folder 3)
- Journals, Jun 1922-Jul 1924 (Box 899, Folder 4)
- Journals, Jan 1924-Apr 1925 (Box 899, Folder 5)
- Journals, Nov 1928- Nov 1929 (Box 899, Folder 6)
- College Notebooks, 1890 (Box 899, Folder 7)
- Notebooks- miscellaneous, undated (Box 899, Folder 8)
- Coordination Notes I, undated (Box 900, Folder 1)
- Fitness and Coordination Notes II, 1922 (Box 900, Folder 2)
- Fitness and Coordination Notes III, 1923 (Box 900, Folder 3)
- Coordination Notes IV, 1924 (Box 900, Folder 4)
- Coordination Notes V, undated (Box 900, Folder 5)
- Coordination Notes VI, 1927-1929 (Box 900, Folder 6)
- Coordination Notes VII, undated (Box 900, Folder 7)
- "An Academic Dog", undated (Box 901, Folder 1)
- "Achilles calls on Betty Harris", 1907 (Box 901, Folder 2)
- "Achilles Goes to Chicago", undated (Box 901, Folder 3)
- "The Advantages of Trucking", undated (Box 901, Folder 4)
- "Air-man and the Tramp", 1918 (Box 901, Folder 5)
- "Also Concerning Pie", undated (Box 901, Folder 6)
- "Andy Meets a Coward", 1911 (Box 901, Folder 7)
- "Another Woman", 1916 (Box 901, Folder 8)
- "At the End of the Rainbow", undated (Box 901, Folder 9)
- "At West Point", undated (Box 901, Folder 10)
- "Aunt Jane", 1915 (Box 901, Folder 11)
- "The Baby Muse", 1900 (Box 901, Folder 12)
- "A Back Number", undated (Box 901, Folder 13)
- "Biddy Macgluffin", 1878 (Box 901, Folder 14)
- "Billy Boy", undated (Box 901, Folder 15)
- "The Bridge", undated (Box 901, Folder 16)
- "The Butterfly", undated (Box 901, Folder 17)
- "By the Waters", undated (Box 901, Folder 18)
- "Cannon's Fleet", undated (Box 901, Folder 19)
- "Captain Ethan's Victory", 1919 (Box 901, Folder 20)
- "The Chief End of Man", undated (Box 901, Folder 21)
- "The Chilcote Cabinet", undated (Box 901, Folder 22)
- "A Child's Street", undated (Box 901, Folder 23)
- "The Chinese Coat", undated (Box 901, Folder 24)
- "A Chosen City", 1905 (Box 901, Folder 25)
- "Conscience Money", 1923 (Box 901, Folder 26)
- "Constantia Encounters the War Tax", undated (Box 901, Folder 27)
- "A Country Auction", 1893 (Box 901, Folder 28)
- "Court Lady", undated (Box 901, Folder 29)
- "Dan Cupid Again", undated (Box 901, Folder 30)
- "The Day Shall Declare It", undated (Box 901, Folder 31)
- "The Day the Clock was Set Ahead", 1919 (Box 901, Folder 32)
- "Dr. Cabot's Two Brains", 1891 (Box 901, Folder 33)
- "The Face in the Car Window", 1908 (Box 901, Folder 34)
- "A Failure", 1886 (Box 901, Folder 35)
- "The First Snow", undated (Box 901, Folder 36)
- "The Flute-Player, 1908 (Box 901, Folder 37)
- "Founders Day at Vassar College", undated (Box 901, Folder 38)
- Fragments, undated (Box 901, Folder 39)
- Fragments and Notes, undated (Box 901, Folder 40)
- "A Free Ride", undated (Box 901, Folder 41)
- "The Freedom of John Peabody", 1926 (Box 901, Folder 42)
- "The Future of Edward", 1918 (Box 901, Folder 43)
- "G.B.S. and his Environment", 1901 (Box 902, Folder 1)
- "The Gayley's Mountain Trip", 1900 (Box 902, Folder 2)
- "The Gayley's Vacation", 1901 (Box 902, Folder 3)
- "A Girl of Gray Sea", 1908 (Box 902, Folder 4)
- "The Good God at St. Fiacre", undated (Box 902, Folder 5)
- "The Good Old-Fashioned Handshake", 1896 (Box 902, Folder 6)
- "The Gray Shadow", undated (Box 902, Folder 7)
- "The Green Jacket", 1917 (Box 902, Folder 8)
- "Hannah", undated (Box 902, Folder 9)
- "The Happiest Man God Ever Made", 1888 (Box 902, Folder 10)
- "Happy Island", 1910 (Box 902, Folder 11)
- "Her Goodly Mountain", 1907 (Box 902, Folder 12)
- "A House of Mercy", 1903 (Box 902, Folder 13)
- "The Housetop Room", 1910 (Box 902, Folder 14)
- "If You Must Cook", 1926 (Box 902, Folder 15)
- "In an American Boarding School", 1890 (Box 902, Folder 16)
- "In Search of an Abandoned Farm", undated (Box 902, Folder 17)
- "Inside the Door", undated (Box 902, Folder 18)
- "Isabel Knows", undated (Box 902, Folder 19)
- "Is Blank Verse Lawless?", 1896 (Box 902, Folder 20)
- "An Island Widow", 1922 (Box 902, Folder 21)
- "Jim Eagan's Draft", 1918 (Box 903, Folder 1)
- "John Fairchild's Mirror", undated (Box 903, Folder 2)
- "Joseph Bimeler's Investment", 1895 (Box 903, Folder 3)
- "A Judgment on them", undated (Box 903, Folder 4)
- "Kate Wetherill", 1900 (Box 903, Folder 5)
- "A Key to Ibsen", undated (Box 903, Folder 6)
- "Laboratory English", 1928 (Box 903, Folder 7)
- "Laboratory Exercises in Writing and Appreciation", undated (Box 903, Folder 8)
- "The Lady With Wings", 1914 (Box 903, Folder 9)
- "A Little Dunker", 1906 (Box 903, Folder 10)
- "The Loneliness of Peter Parrot", undated (Box 903, Folder 11)
- "The Many in the Toy House, undated (Box 904, Folder 1)
- "A Man of Fate", 1899 (Box 904, Folder 2)
- "The Man Who Made Poetry Hum", 1922 (Box 904, Folder 3)
- "The Man with the Torch", 1912 (Box 904, Folder 4)
- "Marcus buys a bucksaw", undated (Box 904, Folder 5)
- "Marcus is left alone with the Tree-Agent", 1891 (Box 904, Folder 6)
- "Marcus Seeks a Diversion", undated (Box 904, Folder 7)
- "Marcus Takes Himself Seriously", undated (Box 904, Folder 8)
- "Marcus Turns Off the Water", undated (Box 904, Folder 9)
- "Marcus Writes to His Mother", undated (Box 904, Folder 10)
- "Matthew Arnold's School Life", undated (Box 904, Folder 11)
- "The Middle Distance", undated (Box 904, Folder 12)
- "Miss Cynthia's Rosebush", undated (Box 904, Folder 13)
- "Miss Henrietta's Will", 1919 (Box 904, Folder 14)
- "Miss Somebody's Chair", 1917 (Box 904, Folder 15)
- "Mrs. Bodington's Book", undated (Box 904, Folder 16)
- "Mr. Achilles", 1912 (Box 904, Folder 17)
- "Mr. Peebles' Investment", undated (Box 904, Folder 18)
- "A Modern Version", undated (Box 904, Folder 19)
- "A Mother-in-Law", undated (Box 904, Folder 20)
- "The Musical Village", 1913 (Box 904, Folder 21)
- "On Progress", undated (Box 905, Folder 1)
- "On Walking", undated (Box 905, Folder 2)
- "One of Marcus's Theories Rises Up to Meet Him", 1903 (Box 905, Folder 3)
- "One Way of Love", 1906 (Box 905, Folder 4)
- "The Parlor Car Tramp", 1919 (Box 905, Folder 5)
- "Pet's Husband", 1905 (Box 905, Folder 6)
- "Playing the Game" (fragment), undated (Box 905, Folder 7)
- "A Poet and a Fool", 1904 (Box 905, Folder 8)
- Poetry, 1886-1888; undated (Box 905, Folder 9)
- "A Problem in Economics", undated (Box 905, Folder 10)
- "Professor Raymond's Way", 1890 (Box 905, Folder 11)
- "The Red Cloth Gown", undated (Box 905, Folder 12)
- "Retrospect", 1890 (Box 905, Folder 13)
- "The Return of Eric Bancroft", 1908 (Box 905, Folder 14)
- Reviews and Promotions, 1897-1911 (Box 905, Folder 15)
- "The Romantic Essay", undated (Box 905, Folder 16)
- "St. Augustine", undated (Box 905, Folder 17)
- "School-Teaching", 1878 (Box 905, Folder 18)
- "The Scientist and the Moth", 1905 (Box 905, Folder 19)
- "The Serenade", undated (Box 905, Folder 20)
- "The Shadow Ring", undated (Box 905, Folder 21)
- "Simeon Tetlow's Shadow", 1909 (Box 905, Folder 22)
- "Sissie Johnnie", 1906 (Box 905, Folder 23)
- "Son of a Fiddler", 1902 (Box 905, Folder 24)
- "Sown Wind", undated (Box 905, Folder 25)
- "The Star Ride", 1924 (Box 905, Folder 26)
- "The Story of the Apple Tree", 1902 (Box 905, Folder 27)
- "Suggestions of Beauty", undated (Box 905, Folder 28)
- "The Swift Guest", undated (Box 905, Folder 29)
- "Taste of Apples", 1913 (Box 906, Folder 1)
- "The Teacher in District No. 3", undated (Box 906, Folder 2)
- "Their Mother and the Pardon for the Son in Prison", 1918 (Box 906, Folder 3)
- "This Magic Body", 1946 (Box 906, Folder 4)
- "This Magic Body"- notes, 1946 (Box 906, Folder 5)
- "A Thread of Scarlet", undated (Box 906, Folder 6)
- "The Three Boats that the Two Man Saw", 1917 (Box 906, Folder 7)
- "Three Chances", 1902 (Box 906, Folder 8)
- "Through a Hole in the Ceiling", undated (Box 906, Folder 9)
- "The Tide", undated (Box 906, Folder 10)
- "To -----, Coming to College", 1913 (Box 906, Folder 11)
- "To the Good Gray Poet" and "Walt Whitman", 1890 (Box 906, Folder 12)
- "A Town Guest", 1903 (Box 906, Folder 13)
- "Trees", 1878 (Box 906, Folder 14)
- "Tulip Day-A Story of College Life", 1907 (Box 906, Folder 15)
- "The Turn of the Wheel", 1905 (Box 906, Folder 16)
- "'Twixt Cup and Lip", 1920 (Box 906, Folder 17)
- "Two College Girls Who Waited", 1889 (Box 906, Folder 18)
- "The Two Doctors", 1917 (Box 906, Folder 19)
- "Tyranny of the Guest", undated (Box 906, Folder 20)
- "Uncle 'Bijah's Ghost", 1921 (Box 906, Folder 21)
- "Uncle William", 1906 (Box 906, Folder 22)
- "Under the Red Maple", 1907 (Box 907, Folder 1)
- "An Unfinished Portrait", undated (Box 907, Folder 2)
- "Unfinished Portraits", 1916 (Box 907, Folder 3)
- "The Venetian Beads", 1909 (Box 907, Folder 4)
- "A Village Child", 1905 (Box 907, Folder 5)
- "A Voluntary Exile", undated (Box 907, Folder 6)
- "What Kind of Girls are the Smith Girls?" (editorial), undated (Box 907, Folder 7)
- "When David Fell in Love", undated (Box 907, Folder 8)
- "When Greek Meets Greek", 1902 (Box 907, Folder 9)
- [no folder] (Box 907, Folder 10)
- "Why the Historical Novel is Popular", undated (Box 907, Folder 11)
- "Wings", undated (Box 907, Folder 12)
- "With a College Education", undated (Box 907, Folder 13)
- "Woman in the Alcove", 1914 (Box 907, Folder 14)
- "The Woman Question", undated (Box 907, Folder 15)
- "The York of Maine", 1893 (Box 907, Folder 16)